A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Oscar Harkavy FA623
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Oscar Harkavy
1960-1982
Rockefeller Archive Center
Harkavy, Oscar
Ford Foundation
FA623
28.5 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
As received.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Includes but is not limited to: Correspondence, trip files, subject files, budget records, conference files and papers.
Biographical / Historical
Oscar "Bud" Harkavy (1923-2019) was a foundation officer who worked for 35 years at the Ford Foundation. During his time at the Foundation, he worked in its Economic Development and Administration, Population, and Urban Poverty Programs.
Harkavy joined the Ford Foundation in 1953. His work initially focused on the Foundation's program for modernizing business school curricula. From the 1950s to 1962, he was based in the Foundation's Economic Development and Administration Program, moving from Program Associate, to Acting Program Director, to Associate Director. He started his work with the Foundation's population programming in 1963 as Director of the Population Program. Following a change in the Foundation's program organization, the Foundation moved its population programming into its International Division, and Harkavy served as Officer in Charge of that Population Program from 1966 to 1980. Harvaky spent the remainder of his time at the Foundation as a Chief Program Officer in its Urban Poverty Program. He left the Foundation in 1988.
After leaving the Ford Foundation, Harkavy served as a consultant to the Population Council and a Board Chairman for the Population Resource Council. He helped found the Life After the Ford Foundation Society (LAFF) in 1991. He served as LAFF Vice President until 1995 and then as LAFF President for two years.
Harkavy completed his undergraduate education at Columbia College and earned a Master's Degree in business administration and a Ph.D. in economics from Syracuse University.
- International Centre for Diarrheal Disease Research, Bangladesh, 1974-1980
  - ICDDR -- Ford Foundation Recommendations for Grant Action and Chronology of ICDDR (and Ford Foundation Letter, April 1, 1980 article), 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR -- Meeting of Interim International Committee to Assist in Establishing the ICDDR, Bangladesh (Geneva, February 13-14, 1979) -- Memo and Summary Report (Box 1)
  - ICDDR -- Meeting of the Consultative Group on the International Centre for Diarrheal Disease Research, Bangladesh (Geneva, June 6, 1980), Jun 1980 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR -- Correspondence Concerning Potential Board Members, 1978 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR -- Correspondence with World Health Organization (WHO, Geneva), 1978 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR and Cholera Research Laboratory (CRL) -- Correspondence, incl. Family Planning and General Health-Related Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR and Cholera Research Laboratory (CRL) -- Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - ICDDRB/CRL/International Center for Health Research -- Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - CRL -- Memoranda, Correspondence, 1977 December-1978 February (Box 1)
  - CRL/ICDDR -- Annual Reports (1976-1979), Index to Publications and Presentations, Newsletter, 1976-1980 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR/CRL/International Institute for Research on Health, Nutrition and Population (IIRHNP) -- Correspondence, RGA, Reports, etc., 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - CRL -- Reports, Notes Re: Program Activity and Creation of International Center for Health Research, 1978 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR, Bangladesh -- Reports, Memoranda Re: Family Planning, Bangladesh Consultancies, etc., 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR, Bangladesh/CRL -- Reports Re: Creation of ICDDR, Bangladesh Family Planning and Population Programs, Meetings, Research, etc., 1976-1978 (Box 1)
  - Joint Ford Foundation/ Population Council Asia Regional Population Meeting (Dacca), 1976 April (Box 1)
  - "A Prospective Study of Birth Interval Dynamics in Rural Bangladesh" -- Report, Ford Foundation Dacca Office by Lincoln Chen, et al., 1974 February (Box 1)
  - "What's the Use of a Demonstration Project?" -- Report, Ford Foundation Dacca Office by Colin McCord, 1976 November (Box 1)
  - "Control of Diarrheal Disease Morbidity and Mortality: Some Strategic Issues" by Lincoln Chen Prepared for the Workshop on Effective Interventions to Reduce Infections, 1977 June (Box 1)
- Reproductive Sciences, 1974-1980
  File Plan
  original numbering preserved
  - 1. Reproductive Science Initiative, 1976 February-1980 July (Box 2)
  - 2. Reproductive Research Policy, 1977 March 3-1978 October 25 (Box 2)
  - 3. Reproductive Science -- Foundation Consortium Materials, 1976 August-1978 August (Box 2)
  - 4. Oscar Harkavy Paper, "Funding of Contraceptive Research" Presented Before Royal Society, 1976 (Box 2)
  - 5. International Committee for Contraception Research -- Meetings, 1980 May-October (Box 2)
  - 6. Contraceptive Safety File, 1978-1980 (Box 2)
  - 7. Miscellaneous Background Papers Re: Population/Health/Development, 1975 June-1976 December (Box 2)
  - 8. Medical Ethics -- Patents, Liability -- Contraceptive Development, 1971 (Box 2)
  - 8. Medical Ethics -- Patent Policy, 1974-1981 (Box 2)
  - 8. Medical Ethics -- Research Involving Human Subjects, Safety Protocols, 1975-1978 (Box 2)
  - 9. Greep Report/Contraception/Reproductive Sciences -- Contraception: Science, Technology, and Application -- Proceedings of a Symposium, 1979 (Box 2)
  - 9. Greep Report/Contraception/Reproductive Sciences -- Responses to Greep Advisory Committee Meeting and to Published Report, 1975 February-1978 December (Box 2)
  - 10. UNFPA -- Consultation on Population Assistance Coordination (Geneva, March 15-16, 1979), 1979 March 15-16 (Box 2)
- International Review Group of Social Science Research on Population and Development (IRG), 1975-1981
  - 1. International Review Group (IRG) Draft Report; Oscar Harkavy Paper on IRG -- Donor's Viewpoint, 1979 March (Box 3)
  - 2. International Review Group (IRG) Final Report -- Related Correspondence and Reports, 1977 January-1980 November (Box 3)
  - 3a. International Review Group -- The World Bank -- Report of the External Advisory Panel on Population, 1976 August (Box 3)
  - 3b. International Review Group -- Working papers Leading up to Grant for International Review Group (Urquidi and Miro), 1976 March (Box 3)
  - 3c. International Review Group -- First IRG Workshop on Research Priorities for Population Policy (Colombo) -- Draft Summary Report, 1978 April (Box 3)
  - 3d. International Review Group -- Bernard Berelson -- Demographic Requirements of Fertility Control Technology; Romanian Anti-Abortion Decree, 1978 (Box 3)
  - 3e. International Review Group -- Bernard Berelson -- Social Science Research for Population Policy, 1977 June (Box 3)
  - 3f. International Review Group -- Bernard Berelson -- "Social Science Research on Population" and Other IRG Documents and Related Papers, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - 4. Gavin Jones -- Social Science Research Report on East and Southeast Asia -- Draft Report for IRG, Mexico City, 1978 January (Box 3)
  - 5. Responses to Berelson-Mauldin Request for "New Efforts" Descriptions; Berelson Paper of January 1976, 1976-1979 (Box 3)
  - 6. IRG Meetings, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - 7. International Review Group of Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Carmen Miro -- Reports, Workshop Materials, Program Statements and Status Updates, 1975-1978 (Box 3)
  - 8. United Nations Fund for Population Activities (UNFPA) -- Correspondence, 1970 April-1981 (Box 3)
  - 9. "Population in the Year 2000" -- An ODC Seminar on the 10th Anniversary of the Establishment of the UNFPA, 1979 November (Box 3)
  - 10. United Nations Consultative Meeting on the National Household Survey Capability Programme, 1979 June 21-22 (Box 3)
- Population and Health Files, 1973-1981
  - 1. December Strategy Paper Re: Population; Background Reports and Notes, Comments Re: Population and Development, 1976 (Box 4)
  - 2. Comments on Robert McNamara's Address by Population Office Staff and David Bell, 1977 March 21 (Box 4)
  - 3. The Foundation's Strategy for Work on Population (Ford Foundation information paper, June 1977); Health, Nutrition, and Population Information Paper (Dec 1979), 1977-1979 (Box 4)
  - 4. International Division Reorganization and Related Papers -- Population Program, Representatives' Meeting, etc., 1980 January-September (Box 4)
  - 5. Meeting with Franklin Thomas Re: Population Office, 1979 July 16 (Box 4)
  - 6. Population -- Other Donor Data, 1973 April-1980 June (Box 4)
  - 7. Working Group on Nutrition Materials -- incl. Reports Re: Nutrition Programming, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
  - 8. Working Group on Nutrition and Incidental Papers Re: Health, Nutrition, and Population; Chafkin Correspondence, 1979 September-1980 July (Box 4)
  - 9. Nutrition Papers, 1976 September-1979 February (Box 4)
  - 10. Washington Follow-On -- Materials on DHEW Budget, FY 1979; Bundy-Kretchmer Notes; Notes, Proposals, Reports Re: Reproductive Science and Contraception, 1976-1979 (Box 4)
- Bellagio Population Conferences, 1970-1977
  Arrangement
  Chronological
  - Bellagio I (April 1970) -- Participants List, Papers (Box 5)
  - Bellagio II (June 1971) -- Planning Materials, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio II -- Agenda, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio II -- Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio II -- "The Commitment of Leaders" by David Bell, incl. Drafts, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Interim Committee -- Minutes of Meeting, 1970 September 10 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Group File -- Population Program Proposals, Meeting Notes, etc., 1970 (Box 5)
  - International Population Research Institutes and Bellagio Population Group Interim Committee Notes, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Recommendations/Responses to Bellagio Population Group Steering Committee Re: Population Activities Proposals, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Population Conference Proposals, Reports (1/3), 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Population Conference Proposals, Reports (2/3), 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Population Conference Proposals, Reports (3/3), 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Population Group -- Memoranda, Reports, etc. (1/2), 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Population Group -- Memoranda, Reports, etc., 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio II, 1971 June (Box 6)
  - Bellagio II -- Reports, Abstracts of Reports Submitted to the Conference and Summary of Conference, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio II -- Participants List, Submitted Proposals List, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio Steering Committee Meeting -- Delivery Systems, 1971 April (Box 6)
  - Bellagio Steering Committee Meeting -- Social Research/Population Policy, 1971 April (Box 6)
  - Bellagio II -- Comments on Papers, 1971 March-June (Box 6)
  - Bellagio II -- Agenda, Status Reports, Information Papers, etc., 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio II and III -- Correspondence with Dr. Allan Barnes and Others Re: Bellagio Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- Social Research and Population Policy Summary and Recommendations, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- Third Population Conference -- Progress Reports for Afternoon Session (May 11, 1973), 1973 May 11 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- Third Population Conference -- Summary and Projections, 1973 May 12 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- "The Social Sciences and Development" -- Conference Papers, 1974 February 12-14 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- Third Conference on Population -- Working Papers (published volume), 1974 June (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- "Priorities for Work on the World Population Problem: Bellagio III" -- Information Paper, 1973 June (Box 6)
  - Bellagio IV -- Seminar Held at Ford Foundation Preparatory to OH and DEB Attendance at Bellagio IV (Denmark, June 6-9, 1977), 1977 June 2 (Box 6)
- Population Papers, Conferences, and Trip Files, 1967-1980
  - Development Centre (of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development) -- First Meeting on Population -- Reports, Information Papers, 1968 December 3-5 (Box 7)
  - Commercial Distribution of Contraceptives -- Meeting at the Ford Foundation (April 28-29, 1969) Re: Marketing and Distribution of Contraceptives, 1969 April 28-29 (Box 7)
  - India Population Meeting (Millbrook, September 23-24, 1969) -- Memoranda, Reports (Box 7)
  - Population/Family Planning Evaluation Conference (Marino, Italy, April 1970) -- Evaluation Materials, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - UNDP Population Program -- Possible Committee Members, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Population Crisis Committee -- September 30, 1969 Meeting -- Re: Population Education Campaign (Box 7)
  - "The Foundation's Work on Population" -- Information Paper, 1970 September (Box 7)
  - Advisors on Family Planning in India -- Memoranda, Reports, 1967-1970 (Box 7)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (DHEW) -- Policy Review Report Re: Family Planning and Population Research, 1969 (Box 7)
  - DHEW-AID Population Research File, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) Conference (Paris) (1/2), 1969 November 17-21 (Box 7)
  - Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) Conference (Paris) (2/2), 1969 November 17-21 (Box 7)
  - Domestic Family Planning -- Memoranda, Report, Grants List, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Congressman Bush -- Requesting Harkavy Appearance Before Congress Re: Population Problem and Tax Legislation, Testimony Included, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Nixon Letter (by Harkavy) Drafts and Memoranda -- Funding Population Research and Work, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - UCLA-Harbor General Hospital Ford Foundation Training and Research Program -- Transfer of Program and Electron Microscope to USC, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Tax Reform Act of 1969 -- Ford Foundation Response to Act, Provisions Affecting Foundation Grantmaking, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Rand/World Bank February 19, 1969 Meeting, 1969 February 19 (Box 7)
  - Rand Proposal Materials Re: Population Control, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Investigation of Training Opportunities in Demography and Economic Development, 1968-1970 (Box 7)
  - Press Conference (April 1, 1970) with Science Press and Grantees in Population Field, 1970 April 1 (Box 7)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Monday, 1970 April 20 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Tuesday (1/2), 1970 April 21 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Tuesday (2/2), 1970 April 21 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Wednesday (1/2), 1970 April 22 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Wednesday (2/2), 1970 April 22 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Thursday (1/2), 1970 April 23 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Thursday (2/2), 1970 April 23 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Friday, 1970 April 24 (Box 8)
  - Atlanta -- Grady Hospital, 1967 (Box 8)
  - (Office of) Education, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Lee, Philip -- Memos, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Program Notes Re: Family Planning, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Hardin, Lowell -- Information, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Hathaway, Dale -- Lecture and Program Participation at Stanford University and University of California, Davis Re: Agriculture and Nutrition, 1975 April (Box 8)
  - India Field Office, 1969-1971 (Box 8)
  - International Rice Research Institute -- Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Pakistan, 1972 (Box 8)
  - French Language Resource Base -- Family Planning Program, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Muscat Proposal -- Stimulating Demand for Family Planning, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development Interagency Collaboration Meeting, 1975 January 9-10 (Box 8)
  - DHEW Report, "Implementing DHEW Policy on Family Planning and Population" by Oscar Harkavy (September 5 and 18, 1967) and Working Papers, 1967 September (Box 9)
  - Family Planning Reports and Memo -- Public Health Service and Planned Parenthood, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Ford Foundation Memos Re: Social Science Research and Development, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Ford Foundation/Harvard University Report/Review Re: Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development -- Africa (1/2), 1973-1975 (Box 9)
  - Ford Foundation/Harvard University Report/Review Re: Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development -- Africa (2/2), 1973-1975 (Box 9)
  - Funding Aspects Re: Support of Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development, undated (Box 9)
  - National Center for Health Statistics, 1967 (Box 9)
  - National and Geographic Regions and Representatives -- Funding Aspects, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Population Studies Proposals and Reports (International), 1974 (Box 9)
  - Regional Visits -- Miscellaneous Re: Family Planning Programs, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Report on Family Planning -- Correspondence Re: Report Planning, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Requests for Essays Re: Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Strategy Paper Materials, 1970 July 16 (Box 9)
  - Strategy Paper (Population) -- Draft Comments, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Welfare Administration -- Incl. Departmental Expenditures on Family Planning, 1966-1967 (Box 9)
  - Harkavy's Trip -- Asia, 1968 July (Box 9)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Oscar Harkavy -- Asia Trip, 1968 July 1-25 (Box 9)
  - Asia Trip Notes -- Pakistan, India, Indonesia, 1969 August (Box 9)
  - Pakistan, India, Indonesia Trip -- Planning Memoranda, Itinerary..., 1969 August (Box 9)
  - North Africa Trip, 1970 January (Box 9)
  - Trip Report -- Hawaii, Indonesia, Bangkok, India and Memoranda/Reports Re: Population Problems in Asia and the Pacific, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Trip -- Bellagio, India, Pakistan -- Miscellaneous Documents, 1975 May (Box 10)
  - Asia -- Trip Notes and Miscellaneous Materials, 1977 October (Box 10)
  - Bangkok, Thailand Field Office, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Trip Notes -- Visit of Harkavy, Saunders, Nagel to Brazil and Mexico, 1976 March 6-19 (Box 10)
  - Brazilian Population Studies Project, 1975-1978 (Box 10)
  - PISPAL, 1977-1978 (Box 10)
  - Folder VI -- Informal Trip Notes, Nigeria, 1978 September 24-29 (Box 10)
  - Folder VI -- Paper, "Population and Family Planning in Mexico", 1978 July (Box 10)
  - Folder VI -- Brazil Trip Notes, 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Asian Parasite Control Organization -- 3rd Conference (Hotel New Otani, Tokyo), 1976 October 20-25 (Box 10)
  - Mr. Harkavy's Santiago Trip, 1967 April (Box 10)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings Re: Trustee Planning Project and "The Hungry, Crowded, Competitive World" (OH paper not in folder), 1976 (Box 11)
  - Elsinore Population Meeting Re: Reproductive Biology (1/2), 1972 (Box 11)
  - Elsinore Population Meeting Re: Reproductive Biology (2/2), 1972 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Meetings -- Population and Social Science, incl. Bellagio, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Population Crisis Article (NY Times) and Population Commission Memo, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Population Studies Centers -- Funding, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Preterm -- Re: Manuals for Abortion Services Programs, 1972-1977 (Box 11)
  - Social Science and Management Research on Population -- Asia Meeting, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Social Science, Demographic, and Management Research and June 29, 1971 Discussion (Box 11)
  - Social Science Research -- Population and Development -- Report ("The Volume") -- Comments, Summary, etc., 1974 (Box 11)
  - Trudy Berkowitz -- Review of Population Studies Centers, 1973 (Box 11)
  - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill -- Carolina Population Center -- Ford Foundation Visit, 1976 November (Box 11)
  - Association of American Medical Colleges -- Mr. Bundy's Speech (March 23, 1969), Also Notes Re: India's Population Problem, 1969-1974 (Box 12)
  - Bundy, McGeorge -- Address to AAMC, Ford Foundation "Population" Policy Paper, 1963-1969 (Box 12)
  - Child Growth, Health, and Infant Survival -- Proposals, Reports, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Immigration, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
  - Immigration Policy, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Immigration and Refugees -- Information Papers/Reports, 1980 (Box 12)
  - International Immigration -- Asian Migration to the Middle East, 1979 (Box 12)
  - International Migration, 1979-1981 (Box 12)
  - International Migration -- Solicited Research Program, 1978-1980 (Box 12)
  - McLaughlin, Robert -- Population Grants, Graduate Work at Princeton, etc., 1973-1976 (Box 12)
  - Medical School, Hospital Program -- Population Council -- Re: Family Planning, 1967 (Box 12)
  - Owolabi/Drysdale -- Health, Family Planning in Africa, 1978-1980 (Box 12)
  - Middle East Research Awards Program -- Guillaume de Spoelberch, 1977 (Box 12)
  - "Plans for the Future" -- A Statement by the Trustees of the Rockefeller Foundation, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Population Paper -- "Population Growth and Family Planning in Kenya" and Chronology of Developments of U.S. Population Policy, 1965 (Box 12)
  - Population/Resources Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 12)
  - "The Social Sciences and Population Policy - A Survey" by Edwin Driver -- Report to Population Office, 1970 February (Box 12)
  - Technical Assistance Career Program Memorandum and Population Problems Board of Trustees Docket Item, 1960 (Box 12)
  - UNFPA Contraceptive Development Project -- Meeting, 1981 October 15 (Box 12)
  - West Africa Research Agenda -- Meeting with Professor Mabogunje Re: Interrelationship between Population and Development, 1978 February 27 (Box 12)
  - Middle East Workshop on Multivariate Analysis (Istanbul), 1980 (Box 13)
  - Rockefeller/Ford Competition, 1976-1978 (Box 13)
  - Rockefeller/Ford Competition and Subsequent Social Science Activities -- Harkavy Copies of Reports, Memoranda, 1978-1980 (Box 13)
  - Social Science DAP, 1980 January-August (Box 13)
  - United Nations World Population Conference (Bucharest, Aug 19-30, 1974) (1/2), 1974 August 19-30 (Box 13)
  - United Nations World Population Conference (Bucharest, Aug 19-30, 1974) (2/2), 1974 August 19-30 (Box 13)
- Population Council and Alan Guttmacher Institute, 1963-1981
  - Population Council Evaluation -- Financial/Hayes, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Population Council Evaluation -- ICCR/Steelman, Ryan, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Population Council Evaluation -- IP/Field Responses, Lyle Saunders, 1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Population Council Evaluation -- Miscellaneous Memoranda, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Population Council External Evaluations, 1973 August-December (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Materials, 1963-1967 (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Policy Review -- Miscellaneous Drafts, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Semi-Annual Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Status Report, 1974-1976 (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Miscellaneous Memoranda (1/2), 1974 December-1975 January (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Miscellaneous Memoranda (2/2), 1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Population and Family Planning Reports, Memoranda, Project Lists, etc., 1979 (Box 14)
  - Fred Jaffe and the Alan Guttmacher Institute, 1968-1977 (Box 14)
  - Alan Guttmacher Institute, 1980-1981 (Box 14)